# **Monika Thakur**

Front-End Developer - Curriculum Vitae

**Date of Birth:** 17<sup>th</sup> August 1987 **Current Location:** Pune, India

Marital Status: Single

**Mobile:** +91 9860912421 / 7972379521 **Email:** monika.singh.rathore@gmail.com

### SUMMARY

Recently working for a IT company as a senior UI developer. I have a great passion in understanding how users interact with the digital environment, in order to ensure that everything I design and develop is focused on user experience. I desire to make a difference through my work.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To get to a position that can fully utilize my skills that I have gathered so far.

#### **CURRENT STAND**

In my current company i handle the UI part it is a product company. I like to code in html, and less css and make it very flexible for developers i also handle the javaScript part service integration with Ajax including underscoreJs templates.

#### **SKILLS**

I am not an expert but always looking out for the best solution for a given problem. A few things that I am familiar with so far, are:

#### Web Design

- Web Design
- Application Design
- Responsive
- Usability testing
- Unit testing

#### Software Knowledge

- Adobe Photoshop
- Microsoft Visual studio
- Eclipse, NetBeans
- Sublime text, TextMate

## Code, Markup, and Awareness

- 1. HTML5
- 2. CSS3,SASS,LESS,CSS animations
- 3. Bootstrap
- 4. JavaScript/ECMAScript / (jQuery)
- 5. JSON/AJAX/XML
- 6. UnderscoreJs, AngularJs 1
- 7. Basic nodeJs (Gulp,Grunt).
- 8. Basic ReactJs
- 9. GIT server/bitbucket
- 10. KedoUI
- 11. Highc charts API

# WORK EXPERIENCES (2012 to Till Date)

# Advanz 101 system PVT. / Medsolis PVT LTD (Pune)

**18** Aug 2014 To Till date UI Devloper

# Job Profile:

My responsibility is to provide excellent quality of products which includes HTML5/CSS responsive websites, Bootstrap, grid system, parallax site with responsive. And Service integration with javaScript including underscore templates.

software development Agile/SCRUM

### RECENT PRODUCT

**URL** for web:-

https://build.medsolis.com/web-medsolis/login

• (User: collins) (password: password)

**URL for application Android:-**

• (User: collins, password: password)

• (User: naksh, password: pass)

• (Organization: bld)

# **URL for application Android:-**

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.medsolis.patientApp&hl=en

### **URL for application IOS:-**

https://itunes.apple.com/tc/app/medsolis-companion/id1055355199?mt=8

#### Product name :-

MedSolis health care

# Project description :-

MedRubik provides intermediate platform between Hospitals, Patients and insurance service providers. This application allows Doctors to connect with the patients and track their regular medical activities and vitals information time to time and gives suggestions according to the latest updates from patient.

## Technology:-

Html,CSS,LESS,JavaScript,ES5/ES6,Jquery,UnderScoreJs,NodeJs,AngularJs 1

### Roles and responsibility:

Creating the html pages and and integrating with the REST api services using javaScript,AngularJs in web pages, i am using the underscoreJs to create the templates in application.

#### **URL for Website:-**

http://medsolis.com/

# Technology:-

Html,CSS,JavaScript,Jquery,UnderscoreJs,wordpress blogs

# Past work experience :-

# • Planet web Solution, Sitapura (Jaipur)

**1** June 2013 To July 2014 Senior UI Devloper

Technology:-

Html,CSS,JavaScript,Jquery,UnderScoreJs

# • S.M.O.K.E Technologies, Lal kothi (Jaipur)

**7th** Dec 2012 To 15th Feb 2013 Senior UI Devloper

Technology:-

Html, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery

### • Richsoftwaredevelopers, Mansarover (Jaipur)

**5th** July 2011– To 24th November 2012 Junior UI Devloper

Technology:-

Html, CSS, Photoshop, Jquery, java Script

### **OLD PROJECTS**

http://www.stonerose.com/

http://savingsgalore.com/index.php

http://seobranddev.com/lionskey/

http://seobranddev.com/cars/

http://www.globemploy.com/

http://seobranddev.com/Atouts-nett/

http://www.reponsesplurielles.com

### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

Web designing course from Royal institute 2011 with first grade.

PHP course from DUCAT, Jaipur in 2011 with Grade A.

Core Java certification from MG Techno savy, Jaipur in 2010 with Grade B.

MSC-IT from rajasthan university.